# Jonathan Brunt • Software Engineer

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/jonbrunt">https://github.com/jonbrunt</a> Portfolio: <a href="https://jmbrunt.com">https://jmbrunt.com</a> Email: <a href="mailto:jbrunt.mobile@gmail.com">jbrunt.mobile@gmail.com</a>

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/jonathan-m-brunt Phone: (405) 237-5614

### Summary

A Full-Stack Development Professional with success providing effective solutions for demanding business, technology, and customer requirements. Strengths include extensive knowledge of user interface and user experience, servers, networks, hosting environments, relational and nonrelational databases. A reputation for utilizing an extensive understanding of how to interact with APIs and external touch-points, testing, quality assurance, and security concerns throughout the entire development lifecycle, while fulfilling customer and business needs.

### **Technology Skills**

JavaScript • Python • C • React • Redux • Angular • Node • Express • MongoDB • SQL • Git/Version Control • SASS • LESS • Styled Components • D3.js • Jest • Mocha • Chai • User Interface • User Experience • Testing • Servers • Networks • Hosting Environments • Adobe Creative Cloud • Various Remote Team Collaboration Tools

## **Professional Experience**

Consultant, Houston, TX 8/2007-Present

<u>Tadah Technologies</u> 11/2018-Present

Lead UI Engineer

Develop, maintain, and scale full-stack applications and websites while simultaneously managing the UI team and collaborating with the backend team and management

- Plan and build production applications and websites from inception through completion
- Technologies in use include JavaScript, React, Angular, HTML, CSS, SASS, and Java
- Implement a custom system to ensure that performance, best practices, accessibility, SEO, and the standards of a Progressive Web App are all prioritized, and that expectations are exceeded at all stages of development

<u>Lambda School</u> 6/2018-Present Software Engineer, Teaching Assistant 3/2019-Present

Deliver lectures to students daily, including theory and live coding, while they learn and utilize skillsets of computer science including data structures and algorithms, graphs, theory of computation, processes, and servers, with an emphasis on learning the Python and C languages.

- Drive the implementation of the Teaching Assistant program in the Computer Science Department, as the first individual in this position
- Within weeks of the position's implementation, student Sprint pass rates increased by 15% in the section
- Develop and revise course content in collaboration with instructors
- Select and mentor new Teaching Assistants

Software Engineer, Master Based Progression Supervisor

9/2018-11/2018

Intensely mentored and supervised students beneath SP80 passing standard while they remediated JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, LESS, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, and SQL skillsets.

• Planned and delivered 1:1 daily consultation with students including code reviews, technical and soft skills improvement, and workflow improvement, leading to 88% of students succeeding in remediation.

Software Engineer, Section Supervisor

7/2018-9/2018

Managed six Project Managers, mentored and supervised 40+ students while they learned and utilized JavaScript, HTML, CSS, LESS, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, SQL, Python, Django, and C skillsets.

- Drove the implementation of a Master Based Progression to support students' goals to reach SP80 status and progress to capstone project and graduation
- Planned and delivered one-on-one consultations with staff and students, improving the student passing rate from an initial 60%, to 98% reaching passing status at course didactic completion

Software Engineer, Project Manager

6/2018-7/2018

Managed, mentored, and graded students for skills including JavaScript, HTML, CSS, LESS, React, Redux, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, SQL, Python, Django, and C.

• Results enabled 100% of students to achieve a passing rate of 80%+ on exams

**BPM Marketing** 

8/2018-11/2018

Software Engineer

Hired on a part time basis to develop, maintain, and scale a portfolio of full-stack websites and applications for 10+ clients by leading web and application development projects.

- Improved the front-end of various retail sites
- Technologies used included JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SASS, PHP, multiple custom Content Management Systems, ASP.NET, Digital Ocean, Amazon S3, Photoshop, Illustrator, and InDesign
- Scaled the server of a movie premiere website in production to reach 15 million consumers via email to promote the online release date and simultaneously build out the front end

**Independent Consultant** 

8/2017-8/2018

Full Stack JavaScript Development, MongoDB, Express, React, Node

Executed multiple full-stack development projects for independent clients.

**Independent Consultant** 

8/2007-7/2017

Biostatistician, Epidemiologist Consultant

Developed and applied skills needed to understand determinants of disease and improve health and utilized descriptive and analytic approaches to investigate the complex causes of major public health problems.

#### Education

University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston, TX

2006-2007

Public Health / Epidemiology / Biostatistics

University of Houston, Houston, TX

1998-2002

Biochemistry / Chemistry